## Ms Seema Guleria

E-mail: guleria.seema@gmail.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

Wants to work in a competitive, challenging, and professional environment as an administrator where I can use my experience, skills, and knowledge to achieve excellence and growth and establish a successful career for myself.



## **ABRIDGMENT**

- Professional Educational Leader from last 20 years in Education Industry.
- Expertise: Academics & Administration, Planning & Organizational Skills, Curriculum Development, Public Relations & Parental Counseling, Staff Training and Development, Team Building & Administrative, Outcome-based Education & Quality Assurance.
- Educational Trainings and Workshops, Quality Excellence in Academics, Orientation Programmes
- Experience: India and Overseas Schools & Colleges (Senior Secondary Schools, Middle Schools, Colleges)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Presently Working in VSPK International School, Delhi (Sr. Secondary School) as a Vice-Principal Academics.
- 2. (2021-22) Worked in Adriel High School, New Delhi (Sr. Secondary School) as a Vice-Principal Academics.
- 3. (2019 -21) -Worked in VSPK International School, Delhi (Sr. Secondary School) as an Academic Coordinator and QA Advisor (currently handling 4 branches of VSPK International School (Jaipur, Sonipat, Pitampura, Rohini) as a Quality Assurance Coordinator)
- 4. (2019-20) (May- September) Worked with **Delhi International Public School, Rewari (Middle School)** as a **Principal** for 6 Months.
- 5. 2018—2019 >Worked with Olive International School, Doha Qatar as a Senior Academic Coordinator and Campus In-charge: I had joined one of the biggest campuses of Olive School and handled 1200 students of different Nationalities. I worked as a Senior Academic Coordinator and Campus Head. Overall managed more than 150 staff members under my Profile.
  - a. I managed 5 different campuses of Olive as a Quality Analysist.
  - b. I worked as Officiating Principal in Olive International School for 2 Months.
- 6. (2015-2018) -- Worked with Ganga International School Rohini Primary & Middle Branch, as a Founder Headmistress.
- 7. (2012—2015) -- Worked with Julia Gabriel International School affiliated with TRINITY UNIVERSITY LONDON (United Kingdom) and Singapore Government as a Speech and Drama Teacher & Outside School Coordinator for 3 years 5 months: Worked as a Teacher and Outside School Coordinator in 3 schools of West Delhi (PP. International School, (Pitampura), St. Angel's School, (Rohini), Modern Public School, (Shalimar Bagh) handled almost more than 1500 students as a Coordinator and team of 15 teachers.
- 8. (2010—2010) Worked with Presidium as a Head of Computer Science Department for 6 months: Handling of 2 wings: Senior and Junior
- 9. (2007—2010) -- Worked with **Sr. Technical Executive** Associate in **IBM DAKSH** for 33 Months: Handling of overseas Project and clients.
- 10. (2006—2007) -- Worked with **S.D.A.M College** as a **Computer Science Lecturer** affiliated with G.N.D.U Amritsar for one academic session.
- 11. (2005-2006) -- Worked with **Army Institute of Higher Education (B. Ed College)** as a **Computer Science Lecturer and Administrator** affiliated with G.N.D.U Amritsar University for one academic session.
- 12. (2004—2005) Worked with **Utkrisht College** as a **Computer Science Lecturer** affiliated with G.N.D.U Amritsar University for one academic session.
- 13. (2003-2004) Worked with **KLM INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL (Day Boarding, Boarding, Day School)** as a **Computer Instructor** affiliated with CBSE, New Delhi for 15 months.
- 14. (2002) -- Worked with **DPS Dalhousie** (**Day Boarding, Boarding, Day School**) as a **Computer Instructor** affiliated with CBSE, New Delhi for 6 months.
- 15. (1998-1999) -- Worked with NITS Institute as a Computer Instructor for 12 months.

## **WORKSHOPS & TRAINING (Conducted)**

## 1. Workshop conducted in Delhi Public International School for Teachers on the following Topics:

- How to take the curriculum in the class: Effective Classroom Learning and Teaching
- Learning by Doing and Learning with Fun
- Presentation Skills

## 2. Workshop conducted for Teachers in Olive International School Doha Qatar on the following Topics:

- Classroom Management Skills
- Effective Classroom Learning and Teaching
- Learning with Fun

## 3. Workshop conducted for Teachers in Ganga International School on the following Topics:

- Classroom Management Skills
- Effective Classroom Learning and Teaching
- Learning by Doing and Fun
- Time Management & Presentation Skills

## 4. Conducted Workshops for Parents in Ganga International School on the following Topics

- Positive Parenting
- 5. Conducted Teacher's Training for Play School Teachers in Rohini.

# Orientation Programme Conducted: (Parents & Teachers) in the following Schools: Topic: Positive Parenting for the Parents

- 1. Ganga International Schools, Rohini (Grade Pre- Nursery VII) in 2015-2017
- 2. Olive International School Doha, Qatar (Grade I-VIII) 2018-2019
- 3. Delhi public International School, Rewari (Grade Pre- Nursery VII) 2019-2020
- 4. VSPK International School, Jaipur (Orientation Session for Teachers) 2020-21
- 5. Open House conducted for Parents and Teachers

#### SKILLS

- 1. Staff Training and Development, Team Building & Administrative Expertise
- 2. Outcome-based Education & Quality Assurance
- 3. Multi-Task Management
- 4. Planning & Organizational Skills
- 5. Critical Thinking, Problem Resolution, Strong Initiative & Forward-Thinking Mindset
- 6. Time Management
- 7. Presentation Skills & Life Skills
- 8. Expressive skills with Speech and Drama
- 9. Personality Development
- 10. Effective Classroom Management & Teaching
- 11. Lesson Planning & Curriculum Development Expert
- 12. Proficient in Creating and Maintaining Schedules: Academic & Administration Planning
- 13. Public Relations & Parental Counseling
- 14. Research & Reviews
- 15. Communication skills

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

"Education is the most important tool to achieve your dreams in your life."

## "Empowering Educational Excellence"

It's been 18 years I am associated with the Education Industry and working as an Educationist. I enhanced my skills step by step in every role. I handled many challenges successfully and learnt a lot from the great leaders I worked with. It gives me great pleasure and immensely proud that I made a remarkable impression in my every role with my hard work, dedication, self - motivation and honesty. I carry a positive attitude. I am a workaholic person with leadership qualities and believes in professionalism.

I started my journey as a teacher and slowly my efforts and aim lead me towards lots of opportunities to play different roles as **Lecturer**, **Department Head**, **Coordinator**, **Senior Academic Coordinator**, **Campus Head**, **Headmistress**, **Acting Principal**, **Principal**, **Trainer and Quality Assurance Expert.** I enjoyed my journey and always open to learning. I believe that nothing is impossible if the person dares to do.

I worked as Outside School Coordinator in Julia Gabriel School and handled following schools of North West Delhi:

- PP International School
- St. Angles School
- Modern International School

I worked as Quality Analysist and Officiating Principal in Olive International School and handled following campuses:

- Olive International Secondary School Umm Salal Ali
- Olive International Primary & Middle School Thumama
- Olive International School Primary & Middle School Nuaija
- Olive International Primary Campus Abu Hamour
- Olive International School Primary Campus Khartiyat

#### Handled Different Branches of VSPK International School as a OA Advisor:

- VSPK International Sr. Secondary School Rohini, Delhi
- VSPK International Sr. Secondary School Jaipur
- VSPK International Sr. Secondary School Sonipat
- VSPK International Junior Branch Pitampura

## **EDUCATION:**

- 1. 1994-1995 --- 10<sup>th</sup> Standard, Vidya Mandir Public High School, (P.S.E.B) (64%)
- 2. 1996-1997 ---12<sup>th</sup> Standard, S.D Girls College, (P.S.E.B) (62%)
- 3. 1997-2000---Graduation, Bachelor of Arts, A.B College, G.N.D.U Amritsar (60%)
- 4. 1997-1998 --- Diploma in Information Technology from National Institute of Technical studies (75%)
- 5. 2000-2001---Post Graduation Diploma in E-Commerce and Internet Application, A.B.College, G.N.D.U, Amritsar (68%)
- 6. 2001---Certificate in Computer Application (CIC) (70%), Certificate in Computer Computing (CIC) (70%) Indira Gandhi National Open University
- 7. 2004---Indian Akshar Mission Akshar Computer Literacy course in Computer Hardware (70%)
- 8. 2004-2006 --- M. Sc Computer Science, S&D Computer College, M.D.U, Rohtak (75%)
- 9. 2006-2007 --- MCA Computer Science, S&D Computer College, M.D.U, Rohtak (75%)
- 10. 2013-14 --- B. Ed from Durga College of Education, Jammu & Kashmir, (63%)
- 11. 2014-15 --- M. Ed from V.B.S Purvanchal University, Jaunpur (72%)

## PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

- 1. 2015 (January)—LEVEL 3 GRADE 7 (Certification in Graded Examination in Communication Skills) From TRINITY GUILDHALL University London (United Kingdom) with Distinction (89%)
- 2. 2015 (June)—LEVEL 3 GRADE 5 (Certification in Graded Examination in Communication Skills) From TRINITY GUILDHALL University London (United Kingdom) with Distinction (89%)
- 3. 2012 (December) LEVEL 2 GRADE 4 (Certification in Graded Examination in Speech and Drama) From TRINITY GUILDHALL University London (United Kingdom) with Distinction (90%)
- 4. 2013 (February) —JGFTC (JULIA GABRIEL FOUNDATION TEACHING CERTIFICATE FROM JULIA GABRIEL CENTRE, SINGAPORE)

#### ACHIEVEMENTS ----- AWARDS/DISTINCTIONS/PUBLICATIONS

- 1) Worked as a officiating principal in Olive International School Doha and VSPK International School Delhi.
- 2) Worked as CBSE In-charge and worked for Secondary Affiliation for Olive International School, Doha Qatar. 2018-19
- 3) Worked with the Ministry of Education, Qatar for Qatar National School Accreditation for Olive International School, Doha Qatar. 2018-2019
- 4) Recruitments of Teachers, Admin and Heads for different Schools of Delhi & Doha Qatar. 2018-2019
- 5) An Interview is given in DD National Channel regarding The National Campaign" Beti Bachaoo Beti Padaoo" started by Honourable Prime Minister Sh. Narendra Modi in Ganga International School. 2016-17
- 6) Unified Council Appreciation Certificate for Unified International English Olympiad -2015-2016
- 7) A Distinction in Grade 4, Grade 5, Speech & Drama and Grade 7 Communication Skills from Trinity Guildhall London. 2014-2015
- 8) Certification of Participation- Seminar on Quality Assurance in Higher Education participated as Delegate in National Assessment & Accreditation Council, B++ BY NAAC, Bangalore. 20016-2007
- 9) Certificate of Merit in Graduation Bachelor of Arts. 2000-2001
- 10) Publication in Punjab Top Bestselling Newspaper for Merit in M.Sc. Computer Science. 2004-2005
- 11) Best Trainee 1<sup>ST</sup> Runner Up Graduation in IBM DAKSH & Medal Day Winner in Bell Olympics in IBM DAKSH, BELL OLYMPIAD Winner in IBM DAKSH 2007-2010
- 12) BELL Best in RPC Winner and Log me in Winner in IBM DAKSH and Best Performer in IBM DAKSH 2007-2010
- 13) Unified Council Appreciation Certificate for National Level Science Talent Hunt Search Examination 2016 -2017
- 14) Attended Principal's Meet/Seminars conducted by Delhi Police for Schools and Colleges, Macmillan Publications, UPES Campus. 2017-2018
- 15) Workshop Attended in Doha Qatar based on Leadership Skills (Shouldering Higher Responsibilities) organized by Birla Public School Doha Qatar. 2018-2019
- 16) Workshop attended in Delhi conducted by British Council for Leadership Skills in 2019-2020.
- 17) Winner of National Level and State Level Player as a Team Captain.
- 18) Certificate of Merit in Sr. Secondary in English and Economics Subjects AND Certificate of Merit in Sr. Secondary in

Y.W.C Activities

## **COMMUNICATION: Writing, Speaking, and Reading**

English, Hindi, Punjabi

#### **INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES**

Music & Dance, Reading, Travelling, Singing, Cooking, Writing

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

D/O/B 26<sup>th</sup> June 1980
Nationality Indian
Religion Hindu
Sex Female

Address
H/N- 200, Kangra Niketan, Near Arya Samaj Mandir, Outer

Ring Road, Vikaspuri, New Delhi, 110018

Phone: 917290830438

#### **REFERENCES**

- Mr Davis (Chairman Olive International School, Doha) -- 97455512810
- Mr Sri Hari Kartha (HR Olive International School, Doha) -- 97433024613, 97430914724
- Mr M.P Sharma (PWD Govt. Engineer, Delhi) -- 919990600101, 918851226717
- Ms Bhawana Sharma (Principal Scholar's Sr Secondary School, Pathankot) -- 919417997308
- Mr Sushil Kumar Gupta (Chairman Ganga International School, Delhi) -- 9811066950
- Mr S.K Gupta (Chairman VSPK International School, Delhi) -- 9810066929

Signature: Ms Seema Guleria